RG 004:063, Hampton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Hampton Probate Court records
1836-1988
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Hampton District)
8.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1836-1988; Probate files, 1836-1936.
RG004_063
1911-005 and 2012-032
Historical Note
Hampton, Windham County, Town established in October 1786, Parent Towns: Brooklyn, Canterbury, Mansfield, Pomfret, and, Windham
The Hampton Probate District was constituted June 2, 1836, from the Windham Probate District. The Hampton Probate District merged with the Colchester, Eastford (part), and Windham Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Windham - Colchester Probate District, which serves the municipalities of Chaplin, Colchester, Hampton, Lebanon, Scotland, and Windham.
Town of Hampton, Probate District chronology:
October 1786 - June 2, 1836, Windham District
June 3, 1836 - January 4, 2011, Hampton District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Windham - Colchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1836-1927; Bonds, 1915-1988. Contact the probate court to access record books after volume 7. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1836-1936. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1836-1936 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 1 to 7. There are 2 volumes of Bonds numbered 1 and 2. There is 1 unnumbered volume.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-005 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Hampton
Places:
Hampton (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1936 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-6, 1836-1917; probate files, 1836-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 15, 1911 (1836-1910); April 25, 1938 (1895-1936). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2012-032 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on April 19, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1836-1988; 6 cubic feet (10 volumes); 2012-032
  - Records, 1836-1858 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1856-1863 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Records, 1857-1875 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1875-1890 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1890-1899 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1899-1907 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1907-1917 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1917-1927 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1882-1915 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1915-1988 (Volume 2)
- Probate files, 1836-1936; 2.5 cubic feet; 1911-005
  - Burdick - Clark, I. (Drawer 1)
  - Clark, J. - Kinyon (Drawer 2)
  - Lanphear - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 3)
- Inventory Control Book, 1836-1936; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1911-005
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest